Guide to the Consumer Reports. Florence Mason papers, 1957-1982 and undated RL.11805
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports. Florence Mason papers
1957-1982 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports (Firm)
RL.11805
12.0 Linear Feet
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. Florence Mason served as Librarian and Assistant to the Director at Consumers Union and correspondent to the United Nations for the International Organization of Consumers' Unions' (now Consumers International). The Florence Mason papers include correspondence, meeting minutes and notes, newsletters and periodicals, reports and other printed materials that primarily document Mason's work with the International Organization of Consumers Unions (IOCU). Topics addressed include consumer protection and education, food issues, economic development, humanitarian assistance, as well as issues relating to women in rural and developing areas. Several files relate to correspondence with Colston Warne, Director of Consumers Union. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: Country File; Subject File
Biographical / Historical
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. Florence Mason served as Librarian and Assistant to the Director at Consumers Union and the International Organization of Consumers' Unions' (now Consumers International) correspondent to the United Nations.
Florence Mason was born in 1896 in Wisconsin. She graduated from the University of Wisconsin in 1921 and worked in the university's Extension Division. From 1929-1939 Mason served as record keeper and librarian at the American Standards Association. Mason joined Consumers Union in 1939 and worked in the Technical Division's Filing Department, helping to set up the Consumers Union library, and advanced to become Assistant to the Director. She was instrumental in the founding of the International Organization of Consumers' Unions (IOCU) and retired from Consumers Union in 1961 to work with that agency, becoming its first correspondent to the United Nations. Mason died in 1990.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Consumer Reports. Florence Mason papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2019.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Cause Marketing Forum. Halo Awards records
Consumer Reports. Advocacy records
Consumer Reports Archives records
Consumer Reports. Colston E. Warne papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Rena Bartos papers
Collection Overview
The Florence Mason papers include correspondence, meeting minutes and notes, newsletters and periodicals, reports and other printed materials that primarily document Mason's work with the International Organization of Consumers Unions (IOCU). Topics addressed include consumer protection and education, food issues, economic development, humanitarian assistance, as well as issues relating to women in rural and developing areas. Several files relate to correspondence with Colston Warne, Director of Consumers Union.
Consumer advocacy; Consumer education; consumer protection; Women consumers; Humanitarian assistance; Economic development; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; International Organization of Consumers' Unions; Mason, Florence; Warne, Colston E. (Colston Estey), 1900-1987
- Country File, 1957-1982; 1
  - Antigua, 1967-1980 (Box 1)
  - Argentina, 1966-1981 (Box 1)
  - Aruba, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
  - Australia, 1964-1979 (Box 1)
  - Austria, 1962-1977 (Box 1)
  - Bahamas, 1963-1980 (Box 1)
  - Bahrain, 1976-1979 (Box 1)
  - Bangaladesh, 1975-1979 (Box 1)
  - Barbados, 1966-1981 (Box 1)
  - Belgium, 1960-1980 (Box 1)
  - Belize, 1971-1979 (Box 1)
  - Bolivia, 1963-1978 (Box 1)
  - Botswana, 1973-1981 (Box 1)
  - Brazil, 1965-1970 (Box 1)
  - Brazil, 1971-1981; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Cameroon, 1976-1979 (Box 2)
  - Canada, 1959-1981 (Box 2)
  - Chile, 1960-1981 (Box 2)
  - China, 1963 (Box 2)
  - Colombia, 1965-1981 (Box 2)
  - Costa Rica, 1966-1980 (Box 2)
  - Cuba, 1980-1981 (Box 2)
  - Curacao, 1965-1981 (Box 2)
  - Cyprus, 1972-1980 (Box 2)
  - Denmark, 1960-1981 (Box 3)
  - Dominica, 1971-1980 (Box 3)
  - Dominican Republic, 1966-1981 (Box 3)
  - Ecuador, 1963-1971 (Box 3)
  - Egypt, 1974-1981 (Box 3)
  - El Salvador, 1976-1979 (Box 3)
  - Ethiopa, 1972-1979 (Box 3)
  - Fiji, 1966-1980 (Box 3)
  - France, 1959-1977 (Box 3)
  - Gabon, 1966-1972 (Box 3)
  - Gambia, 1963-1977 (Box 3)
  - Germany (Federal Republic), 1960-1979 (Box 3)
  - Ghana, 1964-1981 (Box 3)
  - Goa, 1969-1977 (Box 3)
  - Greece, 1963-1979 (Box 4)
  - Grenada, 1968-1980 (Box 4)
  - Guam, 1972-1977 (Box 4)
  - Guatemala, 1966-1980 (Box 4)
  - Guyana, 1968-1981 (Box 4)
  - Honduras, 1963-1981 (Box 4)
  - Hong Kong, 1970-1979 (Box 4)
  - Hungary, 1970-1981 (Box 4)
  - Iceland, 1959-1979 (Box 4)
  - India, 1960-1970; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - India, 1971-1981; 6 folders (Box 5)
  - Indonesia, 1969-1981 (Box 5)
  - Iran, 1963-1977 (Box 5)
  - Iraq, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Ireland, 1959-1978 (Box 5)
  - Israel, 1963-1981 (Box 5)
  - Italy, 1959-1980 (Box 6)
  - Ivory Coast, 1966-1978 (Box 6)
  - Jamaica, 1965-1981; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Japan, 1962-1981; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Kenya, 1963-1980 (Box 6)
  - Korea (South), 1966-1981; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Kuwait, 1975-1979 (Box 7)
  - Laos, 1975-1976 (Box 7)
  - Lebanon, 1970-1972 (Box 7)
  - Lesotho, 1968-1981 (Box 7)
  - Liberia, 1965-1976 (Box 7)
  - Luxembourg, 1963-1980 (Box 7)
  - Madagascar, 1966-1972 (Box 7)
  - Malawi, 1967-1973 (Box 7)
  - Malaysia, 1965-1981; 4 folders (Box 7)
  - Malaysia (IOCU regional office for Asia and Pacific), 1974-1977; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Malaysia (IOCU regional office for Asia and Pacific), 1978-1981 (Box 8)
  - Malta, 1978-1982 (Box 8)
  - Mauretania, 1980-1981 (Box 8)
  - Mauritius, 1967-1980 (Box 8)
  - Mexico, 1966-1981; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Montserrat, 1969-1980 (Box 8)
  - Nepal, 1971-1972 (Box 8)
  - Netherlands, 1959-1979; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Nevis, 1975-1980 (Box 8)
  - New Zealand, 1959-1978 (Box 8)
  - Nigeria, 1963-1969 (Box 8)
  - Nigeria, 1970-1980; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Norway, 1960-1976 (Box 9)
  - Pakistan, 1963-1979 (Box 9)
  - Panama, 1963-1979 (Box 9)
  - Peru, 1968-1981 (Box 9)
  - Philippines, 1963-1981; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Poland, 1963-1977 (Box 9)
  - Portugal, 1970-1977 (Box 9)
  - Puerto Rico, 1963-1981 (Box 10)
  - Rumania, 1974-1978 (Box 10)
  - St. Croix, 1969-1977 (Box 10)
  - St. Kitts, 1971-1977 (Box 10)
  - St. Lucia, 1971-1980 (Box 10)
  - St. Vincent, 1975-1977 (Box 10)
  - Senegal, 1966-1978 (Box 10)
  - Sierra Leone, 1973-1981 (Box 10)
  - Singapore, 1968-1981 (Box 10)
  - South Africa, 1960-1979 (Box 10)
  - Spain, 1963-1981 (Box 10)
  - Sri Lanka, 1962-1977 (Box 10)
  - Sudan, 1978-1981 (Box 10)
  - Surinam, 1973-1980 (Box 10)
  - Swaziland, 1977 (Box 10)
  - Sweden, 1960-1979; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Switzerland, 1963-1977 (Box 10)
  - Taiwan, 1966-1973 (Box 10)
  - Tanzania, 1964-1981 (Box 11)
  - Thailand, 1967-1979 (Box 11)
  - Togo, 1973 (Box 11)
  - Tortola, 1976-1977 (Box 11)
  - Trinidad, 1963-1981 (Box 11)
  - Tunisia, 1976-1979 (Box 11)
  - Turkey, 1975-1979 (Box 11)
  - Uganda, 1963-1974 (Box 11)
  - Union of Soviet Socialist Republics (USSR), 1967-1970 (Box 11)
  - United Arab Emirates (UAR), 1976-1978 (Box 11)
  - United Kingdom (England), 1957-1965; 3 folders (Box 11)
  - United Kingdom (England), 1966-1980; 3 folders (Box 12)
  - United Kingdom (England)--Consumer Council, 1963-1971 (Box 12)
  - United States, 1963-1975; 5 folders (Box 12)
  - United States, 1976-1981 (Box 13)
  - United States--ACCI (American Council on Consumer Interests), 1968-1971 (Box 13)
  - United States--Consumers Federation of America, 1967-1978 (Box 13)
  - United States--Consumers Union, 1959-1980; 4 folders (Box 13)
  - United States--Consumers Union--Boggis reports, Consumers Need Standards, 1963-1966 (Box 13)
  - United States--National Council on Women/International Council on Women, 1963-1970 (Box 13)
  - United States--New York, 1963-1974 (Box 14)
  - United States--Ralph Nader and Public Citizen, 1971-1980 (Box 14)
  - United States--Standards, 1963-1970 (Box 14)
  - Uruguay, 1967-1980 (Box 14)
  - Venezuela, 1965-1980 (Box 14)
  - Vietnam, 1974-1976 (Box 14)
  - Yugoslavia, 1963-1980 (Box 14)
  - Zaire, 1973-1979 (Box 14)
  - Zambia, 1967-1981 (Box 14)
  - Zimbabwe (Rhodesia), 1965-1976 (Box 14)
- Subject File, 1959-1982 and undated; 2
  - Colston Warne, 1959-1982; 1
    - China visit, 1980 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence, 1959-1982; 5 folders (Box 15)
    - Reports from Florence Mason, 1961-1963 (Box 15)
    - Reports from Florence Mason (binders), 1961-1971; 3 folders (Box 16)
  - IOCU (International Organization of Consumer Unions), 1960-1982 and undated; 2
    - Aid fund, 1964-1965 (Box 16)
    - Articles of foundation, 1960 and undated (Box 16)
      Scope and Contents
      Includes foundational and charter documents; IOCU: What It Is and How It Works
    - Correspondence, 1962-1982; 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Council meetings and reports, 1962-1972 (Box 16)
    - Lists, mailings, etc., 1973-1976 (Box 16)
    - Luise Addiss (IOCU representative to UNICEF), 1972-1980 (Box 16)
    - Meetings, 1962-1978; 4 folders (Box 17)
    - Meetings--10th World Congress, 1981; 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Meetings--Council, 1981 (Box 17)
    - Meetings--Executive, 1980 (Box 17)
    - Meetings--Executive, Council and Committee materials, 1979-1980 (Box 17)
    - Meetings--Executives's Annual Report, 1978-1979 (Box 17)
    - Meetings--Minutes of COPOLCO meeting, 1980 (Box 17)
      COPOLCO is the acronym for the International Standards Organization's Consumer Policy Committee
    - Meetings--Second meeting of the Working Group on Library and Documentation, 1980 (Box 17)
    - Meetings--Seminar on Law and the Consumer, 1980 (Box 17)
    - Meetings--Testing Committee, 1979-1981 (Box 18)
    - Meetings--Workshop on Consumer Reporting, 1980 (Box 18)
    - Persia Campbell, 1962-1973 (Box 18)
    - Publications, 1961-1980; 2 folders (Box 18)
      Pamphlets and reports in English, Italian, French
    - Publications--A Digest of the Leading Consumer Movements of the World, 1962 (Box 18)
    - Publications--Consumer Problems in a Development Country (Greta Bergstrom), 1963-1964; 2 folders (Box 18)
      Photographs from Uganda, Tanzania, Kenya
    - Publications--Directories, 1971-1974 (Box 18)
    - Publications--Directories, 1976 (Box 19)
    - Publications--International Organization of Consumers Unions 1960-1981 (Eirlys Roberts) (Box 19)
  - Jan Van Veen, 1960-1981; 3
    - Correspondence, 1960-1971; 6 folders (Box 19)
      Jan H. Van Veen was Executive Secretary of IOCU
    - Correspondence, 1972-1981; 4 folders (Box 20)
  - United Nations, 1960-1980; 4
    - Correspondence, 1960-1979 (Box 20)
    - FAO (Food and Agriculture Organization), 1962-1980; 3 folders (Box 20)
    - ISO (International Organization of Standards), 1961-1964 (Box 20)
    - OPI (Office of Public Information), 1961-1977 (Box 21)
    - UNESCO (United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization), 1962-1978 (Box 21)